准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
你的鞋带
没系好
翻译: 1440kHz
导演
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
系鞋带之歌 作曲及演唱
小蜗
Gary
我刚只是在找体育频道  小蜗
I was just looking for the sports channel, Gary
请进
Come in
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
要看下我的新鞋吗
want to see my new shoes?
鞋子太棒了  派大星
Those are great, Patrick
来看看穿你脚上会是什么样的
Let's see what they look like on your feet
你就不看看穿我手上的样子吗
Wouldn't you rather see them on my hands?
好吧
Okay
我们还能把手套戴脚上
And we can wear gloves on our feet
也能把帽子戴屁股上
and hats on our captain's quarters, too
其实
Actually
我要坦白一件事
I have a confession to make
我不知道要怎么系鞋带
I don't know how to tie my shoelaces
知道你交了我这么个朋友有多幸运吗
Do you know how lucky you are to have a friend like me?
知道
Yes
看着这个结
Look at this knot
有没有见过系得比这还要好的鞋带
Have you ever seen
a more perfectly executed shoe-fastening bow?
天啊
Gosh
大概没有
probably not
我打小就学会了  派大星
I learned when I was just a boy, Patrick
我很愿意倾囊相授
and I'm willing to pass on what I know
到那坐好
Go sit over there
来让我这位老专家教你怎么系
and let an old pro show you how to do it
注意看好了  派大星
Pay close attention, Patrick
先要一只手拿一条鞋带
Well, you start by taking one lace per hand
然后要
and then you
就得
you got to
绕个  个
loop the, the
你确定知道要怎么系吗
Are you sure you know how to do it?
派大星别顶嘴
Patrick, please
系鞋带要安安静静心平气和才行
shoe-tying requires peace and quiet
好  我刚讲到哪了
Okay, where was I?
你鞋带还是没系好
Your shoes are still untied
看来你是不想我教你系鞋带了
Well, I guess you don't want me to show you how to do it
对不起
I'm sorry
我不会再插嘴了
I won't interrupt anymore
想起来了
I've got it
系鞋带的第一条规矩是
The first rule of shoe-tying is
先从右脚系起
"always start with your right foot"
现在课程即将正式开始
Now the lesson will officially begin
这样不对
That's not right
明白吧
Get it?
不
Not
对
right
不懂
No
好  不闹了
Okay, no more fooling around
系好了
I got it
那是干啥
What was that?
你没事吧  海绵宝宝
Are you okay, SpongeBob?
派大星  你不是干啥要来不及了吗
Patrick, aren't you late for something?
上厕所  你说得对
The poop deck, you're right
只能以后再来上课了
We'll have to do this lesson later
再见  海绵宝宝
Bye, SpongeBob
真不敢相信我会忘掉要怎么系鞋带了
I can't believe I've forgotten how to tie my own shoes
自打我记事起  这鞋带就已经系好了
They've been tied for as long as I can remember
还好  好好睡一晚上就会记起来的
Well, I'll remember after a good night's sleep
没什么大不了
No big deal
我迟早都会记起来的
I'll remember sooner or later
因为我准备好了
'Cause I'm ready
我
I'm
准备
read
我准备
I'm read
蟹堡王
我准备
I'm read
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
不好
Oh, no
不能让派大星看到我还没系好鞋带
I can't let Patrick see I still haven't tied my shoes
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
你变矮了
you're shorter
你最近是不是在节食
Have you been dieting?
海绵就该有个海绵样
Well, a sponge has to look his spongiest
我得上班去了
Well, I got to get to work
真见鬼
Oh, barnacles
我还是躺这好了
Maybe I should just lay here
蟹黄堡不会自己做好的  海绵宝宝
Those patties aren't gonna cook themselves, SpongeBob
他说得对
He's right
得去做蟹黄堡
Got to make Krabby Patties
不管鞋带系没系好
Laces or no laces
只要站在这么一个地方就行
I just have to stand in this one spot
哒哒
Ta-da
完美的蟹黄堡
A perfect patty
好了  海绵宝宝
All right, SpongeBob
递过来
Hand it over
怎么
Well?
章鱼哥  我有个办法
Hey, Squidward, I've got an idea
你过来拿如何
How about you come get it?
海绵宝宝  你想得可真是美
Oh, gee, SpongeBob, that's a great idea
然后就要让我做蟹黄堡
And maybe I should cook the patties
再然后洗盘子
and do the dishes
再然后穿方裤子
and wear square pants
再然后住菠萝屋
and live in a pineapple
还要让你加入失业大军
while you wait in the unemployment line
不
No
那就马上把蟹黄堡递过来
Then bring that patty here now
好  章鱼哥
Okay, Squidward
我来了
Here I come
我这就来
I'm coming over
我要把蟹黄堡递给你
I'm bringing the patty to you
蟹黄堡来了
Here comes the patty
没问题
No problem
我要把
I'm walking
蟹黄堡
the Krabby Patty
带给章鱼哥
over to Squidward
好了  章鱼哥
All right, Squidward
我要把蟹黄堡给你
I'm giving you the patty
这都是为了饥饿的顾客们
for the hungry customer
让他们把蟹黄堡吃掉
so they can eat it
等带到你手里那会儿
when I give it to you
也就是现
which is right
在
now
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
我在这
I'm over here
动作快
Now move
好  章鱼哥
Okay, Squidward
只要慢慢动腿
Just slowly move your leg
走过去
Walk over there
拿好
with the
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
对不起  章鱼哥
I'm sorry, Squidward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我再做一个好了
I'll just make another
海绵
Sponge
等下
Hold it
让我先
Let me just
等下
Hold it
抱歉  章鱼哥
Sorry, Squid
对不起
Sorry
怎么这么慢啊
What's the holdup?
我心脏好像停跳了
I think my heart just stopped
都是海绵
It's Sponge
宝宝的错
Bob's fault
海绵宝宝的错
SpongeBob's fault
我完了
I failed
我的事业完了
My career is over
对不起  锅铲
I'm sorry, spatula
对不起  帽子
I'm sorry, hat
蟹黄堡
对不起  地板
I'm sorry, floor
对不起  蟹黄堡
I am sorry, Krabby Patties
我想想  表示快乐的五个字母的单词
Let's see, a five-letter word for happiness
钱
"Money"
这是咱体验过最烂的服务
This is the worst service we've ever had
去海之霸好了
We're going to the Chum Bucket
老板
等等
Wait
别走
Don't go
好啊  我们一定要走
Oh, yeah, we are definitely out of here
等等  别走
Wait, don't go
我的钱全都走出去了
That's me money walking out the door
跟我说这是什么意思  章鱼哥先生
What's the meaning of this, Mr. Squidward?
都是海绵宝宝的错
It's SpongeBob's fault
海绵宝宝  给我出来
SpongeBob, get out here
出来点
More
再出来点
全身都给我出来
All the way, boy
怎么回事  海绵宝宝
What be the matter, SpongeBob?
这种事我都该让你走甲板落海身亡了
I ought to make you walk the plank for this
对不起  蟹老板
I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs
我只是
it's just that I
我
I
怎么了
Yes?
我
I
我  我
I, I
怎么怎么怎么
Yes, yes, yes?
我我我
I, I, I
有话快说  小子
Out with it, boy
什么事
What is it?
我忘记怎么系鞋带了
I forgot how to tie my shoes
就这点事
That's all?
你会教我怎么系吗
So you'll show me how?
我不穿鞋
I don't wear shoes
请问你能教我怎么系鞋带吗
Could you show me how to tie my shoes?
我这是鳍
Fins?
请问你能教我怎么系鞋带吗
Could you show me how to tie my shoes?
我是很想教
Well, I would
可惜我只是条鳗鱼
but, sadly I am only an eel
请问你们有谁可以教我怎么系鞋带吗
Could any of you show me how to tie my laces?
请问你你你你你还有你
Could you, you, you, you, you or you
能教我怎么打个结吗
show me how to tie a knot?
请问你能教我怎么打个小结吗
Could you show me how to tie a simple knot?
请问你能教我怎么系鞋带吗
Could you show me how to tie my shoes?
啊
Arr
我只是幅画着人头的画
I be just a painting of a head
有谁知道怎么打个结
Doesn't anybody know how to tie a knot?
有人说到打结了吗
Did somebody say knot?
我说的
I did
你是不是想打结啊
So, you want to tie knots, do ya?
想不想啊
Well, do ya?
很想  飞天魔鬼先生
Yes, please, Mr. Flying Dutchman, sir
那你就找对飞天的魔鬼了  小子
Then you've come to the right flying ghost, kid
你眼前看到的就是
You're looking at
三千年以来的打花结大赛冠军
the first place winner in the fancy knotting contest
for the last 3,000 years
万岁
Hooray
你别给我那样子
You're gonna have to not do that
别拿你大眼睛盯着我
And stop staring at me with them big old eyes
快退后  看我打结
Now, stand back and watch me be knotty
看好了
Behold
蝴蝶脆饼结
The pretzel knot
双重钻石结
The double diamond knot
方形结
The square knot
巨蟒结
The constrictor
消化道结
The gut knot
枕头结
The pillow knot
蝴蝶结
The butterfly knot
等等  还有呢
Wait, there's more
链环结
The monkey chain
猴拳结
The monkey's fist
猴子结
The monkey
还有个圆环结
This one here's a loop knot
又叫做一拉即解方便结
otherwise known as the poop loop
方便
Poop?
系得太好了  飞天魔鬼先生
Those are great, Mr. Flying Dutchman, sir
现在你能教我怎么系鞋带吗
Now can you show me how to tie my shoes?
我都不知道要怎么系鞋带
I don't know how to tie me shoes
我有五千多年没穿过鞋了
I haven't worn shoes for over 5,000 years
不过有时我倒喜欢给我尾巴穿只袜子
But sometimes I like to wear this little sock
over me ghostly tail
现在不行  小蜗
Not now, Gary
我现在没心情  小蜗
I'm not in the mood, Gary
别烦我跟我没系好鞋带的鞋了  小蜗
Just leave me and my untied shoes alone, Gary
好  小蜗
Okay, Gary
我这就听你说
you have my attention
小蜗
Gary
不会吧
Well, I'll be
你居然会系鞋带
You can tie shoes
我的天啊
Hopping clams
你怎么学会的
How did you learn how to do that?
想来学怎么系鞋带
Want to learn how to tie your shoe
这事非常的简单
It's a very easy thing to do
快坐下来  教你独门秘诀
You sit on down and I'll give you the scoop
是什么呢
What's that
绕个圈
就叫绕个圈
It's called the loop-dee-loop
一只手各拿一条鞋带
You got to take a lace in each hand
先往上绕再往下绕
You go over and under again
绕个圈再拉一拉
You make a loop-dee-loop and pull
你的鞋子就能酷
and your shoes are looking cool
先往上往下  从左到右
You go over and back, left to right
绕个圈再拉紧点
Loop-dee-loop and you pull them tight
好比兔子耳朵或者蝴蝶结
Like bunny ears or a Christmas bow
束紧之后就大功告成
Lace 'em up and you're ready to go
绕个圈再拉一拉
You make a loop-dee-loop and pull
你的鞋子就能酷
and your shoes are looking cool
绕个圈再拉一拉
You make a loop-dee-loop and pull
你的鞋子就能酷
and your shoes are looking cool
章鱼哥的
休息日
翻译: 1440kHz
导演
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊  美好的春日
Ah, beautiful springtime
对多数人来说是嬉戏玩乐的好时光
A time of fun and frolic for most
蟹堡王
但对这位可怜懒虫就不是
but not for this poor slob
多美好的一天啊
What a beautiful day
而我却在这
And here I am
困在这么一座高胆固醇的监狱里
trapped in a prison of high cholesterol
不会有人星期天来这的
No one ever comes in on Sunday
为什么蟹老板就不能放我们回去
Why can't Mr. Krabs just let us go home?
海绵宝宝  别按铃铛了
SpongeBob, stop ringing this bell
我只是测试一下
I was just testing it
有人点餐我就会按铃铛的
I will ring the bell when there's an order
可是
But
根本就没客人
there's no customers
整天下来一个客人也没来
There hasn't been one all day
等多久也不会有人来
and there isn't going to be any
一份蟹黄堡马上来
One Krabby Patty coming up
不
No
好像是我钱掉地上的声音
That sounds like me money dropping
外面这是怎么了
What's going on out here?
我的宝贝
My babies
滚开  野蛮人
Get away, barbarian
看你们干了什么好事
What have you done?
干干净净的钱
Nice clean money
被玷污了
soiled
我会照顾好你们的
I'll take care of you
老爸会把你们清干净的
Papa clean you up
都让开
Clear the way
不不不
No, no, no
别哭了  小家伙
don't cry, little ones
怎么了  蟹老板
What's wrong, Mr. Krabs?
我的硬币
Me dime
不
No
接到了
I got it, boy
怎么
What the?
卡住了
It's stuck
快帮我一把  海绵宝宝
You got to help me, SpongeBob
你必须松手把硬币放了
You've got to let go of the dime
我有十种不同的充分理由
I can think of ten good reasons
绝对不松手把硬币放了  小子
to never let go of a dime, boy
肯定还有别的不放钱的办法
There's got to be another way
抓住我屁股  然后拉
Grab me captain's quarters and heave
我的胳膊
Me arms
不会吧  又来了
Oh, no, not again
等等
Wait
章鱼哥
Squidward
我住院期间  这里的事情交给你管
I'm putting you in charge of things around here
while I'm gone
包在我身上  老板
You can count on me, sir
保重  早日回归
Take care, hurry back
尽快康复
Get well soon
我们深深挂念着你
You're in our thoughts
多保持乐观  少点焦虑
Takes more muscles to frown than to smile
好了  海绵宝宝
Okay, SpongeBob
来干正事吧
let's get down to business
我作为新任经理的第一份公务
My first official act as new manager
就是让你升职
is to give you a promotion
真的吗
Really?
由你来负责收银
You get to run the cash register
我来收银
The cash register?
章鱼哥  谁要来做蟹黄堡
Squidward, who's going to work the grill?
就是你
You are--
这也是所谓升职的一部分
it's part of the promotion I mentioned earlier
你现在要戴两顶帽子了
You'll be wearing two hats now
由你负责接单
You're going to take the orders
再由你把餐点做出来
then you're going to make them
这是我一生最美好的一天了
This is the best day of my life
我也一样
Me, too
可是等等  如果我既收银又做蟹黄堡
But wait, if I'm running the register and the grill
那你要干什么
what are you going to do?
我有点特别重要的老板差事要做
I've got some very important boss-like errands to run
等会见
See you later
章鱼哥
Squidward
什么事
What is it?
你忘了教我怎么用
You forgot to teach me how to use
收银机
the cash register
按按钮  把钱放进去
You push the button and put the money inside
行  之后全靠你自己了
Okay, you're on your own
真不敢相信真的会有这种事
I can't believe this is really happening
今天  美好生活开始了
Today I start living
章鱼哥啊  你这回表现可真出彩
Well, Squidward, you've really
outdone yourself this time
放松享受的美好日子
A beautiful day of relaxing and pampering
还带薪
with pay
我估计是有点愧对可怜的海绵宝宝了
Guess I do feel kind of bad for poor little SpongeBob
留他一个人在那
all by his lonesome
全都会过去的
It will pass
他可能就单纯站收银台那边
He's probably just standing at the register
脸上挂着傻傻的笑容
with that stupid grin on his face
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
派大星
Hey, Patrick
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
能给我换两毛五的零钱吗
could you give me change for a quarter?
没问题
No problem
拿去吧
Here you go
谢谢
Thanks
我忘了教他怎么换零钱了
I forgot to tell him how to make change
海绵
Sponge
宝宝
Bob
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
差事都办完了吗
All done with those errands?
没办完
No, I am not
我刚想起来我要换一块钱零钱
I just remembered I needed change for this dollar
你是要四个两毛五
Do you want four quarters
还是十个一毛
or ten dimes
还是二十个半毛
or 20 nickels
还是一百个一分
or 100 pennies
还是一个两毛五三个一毛
or one quarter, three dimes
七个半毛十个一分
seven nickels and ten pennies
或者要是你能再拿五块钱出来
or, if you give me a five-dollar bill
就能换
your options are
好
All right
再见
Goodbye
太棒了
This is great
我的休息日
My day off
不用想太多  放松就好
no worries just relaxation
我可是老板  这都是我应得的
I'm the boss, I deserve this
不会有事的
Everything will be fine
反正今天也不会来客人
There won't be any customers today anyway
他估计会无聊地光站在那
He'll probably just stand there bored
海绵宝宝  无聊
SpongeBob, bored
有点无聊了
Getting kind of bored
我在干什么啊
What am I doing?
我在浪费我宝贵的放松时间
I am wasting valuable relaxing time
就这么一件事
that's what I'm doing
说真的  这种事可能性会有多大
I mean, really, what are the odds?
海绵宝宝让蟹堡王失火了
SpongeBob setting the Krusty Krab on fire?
需要服务吗  先生
May I help you, sir?
是我  你个白痴
It's me, you dunce
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
差事办得怎么样了
How are those errands going?
你这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我忙得很
I'm very busy
那是当然的了
I'm sure you are
我不喜欢你的语气
I don't like your tone
那是当然的了
I'm sure you are
这样如何
How's that?
干好你的活
Just do your jobs
遵命  章鱼哥老板
Aye-aye, Mr. Tentacles
天啊  怪不得蟹老板让他管蟹堡王
Boy, no wonder Mr. Krabs put him in charge
一定要
Must
休
re
息
lax
看看你自己
Look at yourself
都快失去你的蓝色光泽了
You're losing your bluish glow
别老想这么多了
Stop worrying so much
快跟着我念
Now, repeat after me
你不会回蟹堡王去
You will not go back to the Krusty Krab
我要灭了蟹堡王
I will destroy the Krusty Krab
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你的事
Have you finished --
没
No
就这样
That's it
不管我想的都什么乱七八糟的玩意
No matter what sick fantasies run through my mind
我也绝对不会回蟹堡王去
I will not go back to that restaurant
你的事办完了吗
Have you finished those errands?
事  事
Errands, errands
你的事办完了吗
Have you finished those errands?
没有  我的事都没办完
No, I am not finished with those errands
而且永远办不完  不要再问我了
and I never will be, so quit checking up on me
我知道你有什么企图
I know what you're up to
每次你搞砸工作都要逼我回来看
Forcing me to come back here every time you mess up
可我没
But I haven't
好  也许你现在还没搞砸工作
Okay, maybe you haven't messed up yet
但之后一定会
but you will
一定会
You will
等你真搞砸的那会儿
And when you do
我一定会逮到你
I'll be there
一定会逮到
天啊  章鱼哥实在太敬业了
Gosh, Squidward sure is a hard worker
他让我戴着这两顶帽子的感觉好骄傲
He makes me proud to wear these hats
警戒线 禁止跨越
好了
There
我只要待在这享乐就行了
Now I'll have to stay here and enjoy myself
绝对不去想那个谁
I'm not even going to think about you-know-who
在那个什么地方做那个什么事
at the you-know-what doing I-don't-care
只要
Just gonna
放松
relax
让章鱼哥的休息日
Let Squid's day off
开始
begin
什么声音
What was that?
是海绵宝宝
It's SpongeBob
他在监视我
He's spying on me
检查我是不是真在办差事
to see if I'm really doing errands
但他这样就擅离职守了
But he left his post
这样我就终于能逮到他搞砸工作了
And I've finally caught him messing up
逮到你了  海绵
I caught you, Sponge
枝条
Branch
这是蟹老板要我买的橡皮鸭
Here's the rubber duck Mr. Krabs wanted me to get
逮到你了
I got you now
等着瞧蟹老板发现你是个
Wait till Mr. Krabs finds out you're a
马桶
toilet
你就快疯了  章鱼哥
You're losing it, Squidward
冷静
Calm down
要是再被这种想法冲昏头的话
If I let this get to me again
最后肯定就一路跑到蟹堡王
I'll just end up running down to the Krusty Krab
冲进大门
bursting through the front door
径直走向害我头疼的海绵宝宝面前
up to that yellow headache, SpongeBob
然后他就会说
and he'll say
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
你的事都办完了吗
Are you finished with those errands yet?
我就知道你在里面
I know you're in here
他要回蟹堡王去了
He's headed back to the Krusty Krab
要先他一步到那
I'll beat him there
逮到你了  海绵宝宝
I've got you now, SpongeBob
把衣服穿上
Put some clothes on
真相要大白了
The truth will be revealed
好棒  章鱼哥
Right on, Squidward
急诊
好的  蟹老板
Okay, Mr. Krabs
好好休息
Get plenty of rest
要是哪里不舒服了  就回来复诊
and if things don't seem right, come back
谢谢医生
Thanks, Doc
海绵宝宝  你打败不了我
SpongeBob, you can't beat me
蟹堡王
逮到你了
I caught you now
你以为我不知道
You didn't think I knew
你是我窗外的枝条
you were a stick outside my window
或者是我卫生间里的马桶
Or the toilet in my bathroom
然后在我浴缸里  我
And then you were in my bathtub, and I
然后你
and you
and I
再然后我
and then you
一路
swam
游过下水道
down the drain
再
and
先我一步回蟹堡王
beat me to the Krusty Krab
那是不是表示
Does that mean you're?
对  海绵宝宝
Yes, SpongeBob
我的事都办完了
I am finished with those errands
我很想回来继续负责收银
I guess I want to take my place back at the cash register
我真的很想
I really do
那你可能会想把这个穿上
Then you might want to put these on
章鱼哥  你知道不
Hey, Squidward, you know what?
看  咱好像忘把关门标换成开门标了
Look, we forgot to switch the "Closed" sign to "Open"
关
开
我们本来可以休息一整天
It's almost like we could have taken the whole day off